A Guide to the Films of University of Virginia Events, 1963-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
A Guide to the Films of University of Virginia Events 1963-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-4/2/12.961
The collection consists of 45 movie reels.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Archival transfer from University of Virginia Information Services, August 13,1996.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 45 movie reels of events at the University of Virginia, 1963-1976. The titles of the films are taken from labels attached to the reels. Topics include: the College Bowl, 1963; President's reception, 1968; student demonstrations, 1969-1970; NASA Kohoutek Project, 1973; and Frank L. Hereford's inauguration; as well as a copy of "The eye of Thomas Jefferson," 1976.
Other topics include reception at Carr's Hill, 1967; Registration day, ca. 1967; cheerleaders; Founders Day 1975, 1976; students eating; dormitories, ca. 1967; Clinch Valley; Baseball facilities; co-rec volleyball; football; U. Va. vs. UNC basketball game, spring 1975;'V' on basketball floor; snow scenes; Guys and Dolls; Country Wife, 1975; Darden moves, 1975; summer changes; University prospectives, 1974; students chemistry lab; band day; U. Va. in autumn; spinal cord injury center; fine arts library.
Contents List
- Eye of Thomas Jefferson, Guggenheim production, 1977, 1
- Scenes from University of Virginia Registration, 1967, 2 A
- Scenes from University of Virginia Registration, 1967, 2 B.
- Stein with Taylor, 1975 April 30, 3
- Country Wife, Virginia Players, 1975 Spring, 4
- Carrs Hill Reception, 1967; Around Dorms, ca. 1967, 5
- Fine Arts Library, 6 A
- Spinal Cord Injury Center, 6 B.
- Demonstrations, 1969 February, 7
- Demonstrations, 1970, 8
- Cheerleaders, 9
- Basketball, U. Va. vs. UNC, 1975, 10
- Unknown, 11
- Hereford Inauguration A Roll, 12
- Hereford Inauguration B Roll, 13
- Hereford Inauguration Sound Track Short, 14
- Hereford Inauguration B Sound Track, 15
- Students with Umbrellas, 16
- Reider Films 10-11-12 Head Exteriors All Over, 17
- Clinch Valley, 18 A.
- Baseball Facilities; Football; Co-Rec Volleyball, 18 B.
- Students Eating; Days Class, 19 A.
- Founders Day, 1975, 19 B.
- Scenes from Grounds, 20
- Scenes from Grounds "Good Stuff", 21
- Guys & Dolls, 22 A.
- Guys & Dolls Outs, 22 B.
- Snow Scenes, 22 C.
- Unknown: "Title wpff.cut", 22 D.
- J. Lewis Neuro-muscular, 23
- Band Day A, 24 A.
- Band Day B, 24 B.
- Band Day Tail, 24 C.
- Founders Day, 1976, 25 A.
- Summer Changes; Darden Moves, 25 B.
- "V" on Baskeball Floor, 25 C.
- University Prospectives Intro, 1974, 25 D.
- Students Chem lab, 25 E.
- NASA Kohoutek Project, 26
- Reider Film U.Va. in Autumn, 27